Finding Aid for Ferry Family Papers 1758-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Dexter Mason Ferry, Jr., Papers, 1881-1963
  - Business papers, 1881-1963
    - Properties, 1908-1922
      - Ferry farm (Greenfield), 1908-1922; 6 folders (Box 9)
      - Kirby-Ferry-Farnsworth, 1914 (Box 9)
    - Standard Accident Insurance Co., 1924-1946
      - General, 1924-1941; 8 folders (Box 9)
      - General (including merger with Planet), 1937-1957; 7 folders (Box 10)
    - Triangle (balance, journal, and ledger), 1917-1925 (Box 10)
  - Personal papers, 1884-1960
    - Appointment books and diaries, 1888-1959; 7 folders (Box 10)
    - Army Service, 1917-1945
      - Duty record, 1917-1932 (Box 11)
      - General, 1917-1945; 4 folders (Box 11)
      - Convoy
        - Correspondence, etc., 1918 (Box 11)
        - 1928 (Box 11)
          (photographs)
    - Automobile touring (including honeymoon trip through Virginia), 1900-1910; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Correspondence-Family, 1885-1959
      - Acheson family (cousins), 1909-1956 (Box 11)
      - Coonley, Queene Ferry (sister)
        - 1888-1905, 8 folders (Box 11)
        - 1910-1928, 19 folders (Box 11)
        - 1929-1958, 15 folders (Box 12)
      - Ellsworth, Emma Miller (?), 1921-1956 (Box 12)
      - Ferry, Addie E. (mother),1885-1906, 15 folders (Box 12)
      - Ferry, Dexter M., Jr. (letters penned to), 1888-1905
        - Ferry, Addie E.,1888-1900, 3 folders (Box 12)
        - Ferry, Blanche, 1889 (Box 12)
        - Ferry, Dexter M. (father), 1889-1900 (Box 12)
        - Ferry, Edith, 1889-1893 (Box 12)
        - Ferry, Queene, 1889-1905 (Box 12)
        - Mason, Chloe A. (cousin), 1892-1899 (Box 12)
      - Ferry, Dexter Mason, III (son), 1921-1952
        - Hotchkiss Preparatory School, 1921-1927; 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Princeton, 1929-1931 (Box 12)
        - Personal, 1932-1952 (Box 12)
      - Ferry, Edith (sister), 1889-1893
        - 1880-1883, 8 folders (Box 12)
        - 1884-1893, 14 folders (Box 13)
        - 1884-1889 (Box 13)
          (transcripts)
        - 1880-1886 (Box 13)
          (Pat Young photos of Edith Ferry sketches and watercolors)
      - Ferry, Edith (daughter), 1914-1930 (Box 13)
      - Ferry, Jeanette (daughter), 1926-1946 (Box 13)
      - Ferry, Jeanette Hawkins (wife) (4 folders and 1 scrapbook), 1909-1959 (Box 13)
      - Hawkins-Hays family, 1909-1952; 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Hooker, Blanche Ferry (sister), 1908-1935; 24 folders
        - 1886-1905, 10 folders (Box 13)
        - 1909-1959, 27 folders (Box 14)
        - Ferry Estate, 1908-1916 (Box 14)
      - Mason, Chloe A. (cousin), 1894-1899; 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Miller family (cousins), 1898-1928; 3 folders (Box 14)
      - Myrich, Mary, 1911-1948 (Box 14)
      - Weeks, A. M. (uncle), 1908-1914 (Box 15)
      - Weeks, Dexter (cousin), 1908-1940 (Box 15)
      - Weeks-Webb families, 1912-1948 (Box 15)
      - White, A. E. (cousin), 1901-1940 (Box 15)
      - White, H. Kirke (cousin), 1926-1939 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence-General: Chronological
      - 1892-1893. (Box 15)
      - 1894, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - 1895, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - 1896, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - 1897, 4 folders (Box 15)
      - 1898, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - 1900-1902 (Box 15)
      - 1907 (Box 15)
      - 1908-1909 (Box 15)
      - 1910-1912 (Box 15)
      - 1913-1915 (Box 15)
      - 1916-1917 (Box 15)
      - 1919-1922 (Box 15)
      - 1923-1927 (Box 15)
      - 1928 (Box 15)
      - 1929-1931 (Box 15)
      - 1932-1934 (Box 15)
      - 1936-1939 (Box 15)
      - 1940-1945 (Box 15)
      - 1946-1949 (Box 15)
      - 1950-1958 (Box 15)
    - Education, 1884-1914
      - Detroit Home and Day School, 1884-1886; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Detroit High School, 1890-1891; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - University of Michigan, 1892-1895; 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Columbia University, 1897-1898; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Sprague's Law School, 1894-1900 (Box 16)
      - Scriblerus Club, 1902-1914; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Financial papers, 1898-1959
      - Ferry, Addie (estate), 1898-1922 (Box 16)
      - Ferry, Jeanette H. (estate),1950-1957 (Box 16)
      - Hawkins family (estates), 1938-1947 (Box 16)
      - Hawkins, James (estate), 1911-1923 (Box 16)
      - Hawkins, William (estate), 1912-1952 (Box 16)
      - Hays, Margaret (estate), 1911-1931 (Box 16)
      - Hays, Richard (estate), 1913-1951 (Box 16)
      - Household furnishings appraisal, 1935 (Box 16)
      - Taxes, personal property, 1909-1959; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Trust, Dexter Mason Ferry, 1933-1959; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Medical papers, 1923-1952
      - Doctor Hibbs, 1926-1936 (Box 17)
      - General, 1923-1952; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1901-1959
      - Delta Kappa Epsilon, 1920-1959 (Box 17)
      - Detroit Boat Club, 1907-1959; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Detroit Tennis Club, 1915-1916 (Box 17)
      - Economic Club of Detroit, 1939-1947 (Box 17)
      - Grosse Pointe club, 1924-1928 (Box 17)
      - Huron Mountain cabin, 1934-1950 (Box 17)
      - Merrill-Palmer school, 1929-1955 (Box 17)
      - Omicron Literary Association, 1902-1914 (Box 17)
      - Woodward Cemetery, 1923-1959 (Box 17)
      - Woodward Avenue Congregational Church, 1888-1911 (Box 17)
    - Properties, 1907-1959
      - Grosse Pointe, Jefferson Avenue house, 1912-1937; 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Milfer farm, 1907-1959; 6 folders (Box 17)
      - Milfer trust, 1934-1959; 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Scrapbooks and clippings: Alphabetical, 1885-1905
      - Congregational Church, 1895-1905 (Box 18)
      - D. M. Ferry & Co. fire, 1886 (Box 18)
      - Ferry, Edith (in Santa Fe), 1885-1900 (Box 18)
    - Scrapbooks and clippings: Chronological, 1889-1959; 6 folders (Box 18)
    - Scrapbook, 1901-1914 (Volume 6)
    - Scrapbook, 1914-1932 (Volume 7)
  - Philanthropic materials, 1890-1962
    - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1907-1959
      - 1907-1945, 25 folders (Box 18)
        (includes material on Weber lawsuit)
      - 1946-1959, 12 folders (Box 19)
        (includes 1948 photos of collection)
    - Fine Arts, 1890-1959
      - Arts and Crafts Society, 1915-1959 (Box 19)
      - Ferry, Dexter Mason, Collection, 1894-1939; 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Gilbert, Cass (architect), 1915-1920 (Box 19)
      - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1925-1933 (Box 19)
      - Paintings, 1890-1959; 3 folders (Box 19)
      - Scarab Club, 1922-1941 (Box 19)
      - Scudder, Janet (sculptor), 1919-1920 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1908-1962
      - Boy Scouts of America, 1915-1959 (Box 19)
      - Chicago Theological Seminary, 1922-1959 (Box 19)
      - Children's Hospital of Michigan, 1917-1947 (Box 19)
      - Delta Kappa Epsilon, Omicron Literary Association, 1909-1959 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Citizens League, 1919-1959 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Opera Society, 1931-1934 (Box 19)
      - Detroit Symphony, 1918-1959 (Box 19)
      - Franklin Settlement, 1943-1954 (Box 19)
      - Grace Hospital, 1908-1948 (Box 19)
      - Grosse Pointe Library, 1927-1954 (Box 19)
      - Grosse Pointe Memorial Church, 1919-1959 (Box 19)
      - Grosse Pointe Mutual Aid and Neighborhood Club, 1926-1962 (Box 19)
      - Grosse Pointe Playgrounds, 1921-1926 (Box 19)
      - Leader Dog League, 1941-1948 (Box 20)
      - Michigan League of Planned Parenthood, 1946-1957 (Box 20)
      - National Recreation Association, 1914-1959 (Box 20)
      - North Woodward Congregational Church, 1952-1956 (Box 20)
      - Old Club, 1909-1956 (Box 20)
      - Old Newsboys/Goodfellows Club, 1925-1952 (Box 20)
      - Red Cross, 1917-1942 (Box 20)
      - United Foundation, 1947-1950 (Box 20)
      - Woman's Hospital, 1923-1947 (Box 20)
      - YMCA, 1917-1958 (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Detroit, 1910-1959 (Box 20)
    - Schools, 1899-1960
      - Columbia University (Dean F. C. Keppel), 1910-1943 (Box 20)
      - Cranbrook scholarship, 1950-1959 (Box 20)
      - Ferry, Dexter M., Jr. (school), 1923-1955 (Box 20)
      - Grosse Pointe Country Day, 1915-1940 (Box 20)
      - Lawrenceville, 1908-1960 (Box 20)
      - Liggett School, 1908-1960 (Box 20)
      - Olivet College, 1908-1950; 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Vassar College, 1899-1956; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - University of Michigan, 1910-1960
      - Alumni Association, 1928-1948 (Box 20)
      - Alumni Fund, 1923-1959 (Box 20)
      - Alumni Memorial Hall, 1910-1915 (Box 20)
      - Clements Library, 1937-1947 (Box 20)
      - Emeritus Club, 1946 (Box 20)
      - Fresh Air Camp, 1928-1958 (Box 20)
      - Honorary Master of Arts Degree, 1933 (Box 20)
      - Press, 1928-1957; 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Ruthven, Alexander G., 1929-1948 (Box 20)
      - Stratton, Mary Chase, Fund, 1942-1946 (Box 20)
      - University of Michigan Club of Detroit, 1947-1960; 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Women's League Building Fund, 1924-1931 (Box 20)
  - Political materials, 1899-1959
    - Michigan State Board of Education, 1909-1913 (Box 20)
    - Grosse Pointe City, 1906-1959
      - Bond Register, 1906-1946 (Box 20)
      - Budgets and Financial Statements, 1942; 1944-1952; 3 folders (Box 20)
      - General (), 1920-1959; primarily 1944-1951; 12 folders (Box 21)
    - Scrapbook, State Legislature,1899-1902 (Box 21)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series includes stereograph cards, showing farm activities from the Greenfield Farm in Illinois, 1880s-1890s; photos of the D. M. Ferry Company building in Detroit; interior views of the different rooms of the family home at 31 Winder Street in Detroit, ca.1900; photographs and photograph albums of Dexter M. Ferry, Jr. from the period when he was a student at Detroit Home and Day School, Lawrenceville School, and the University of Michigan, 1889-1896; other Ferry family portraits, including Dexter M. Ferry, Sr.; and photographs showing military convoy coming from Camp Holabird to Detroit in the 1920s.
  - D. M. Ferry & Co./Ferry-Morse Seed Co., 1880s-1946
    - Greenfield Farm in Illinois, 1880s-1890s (Box 21)
      (include stereographic images)
    - Greenfield Farms, J. Thomas drawings, 1890s (Box 21)
    - Buildings in Detroit,1890s-1929 (Box 21)
      (see also oversize in box 22)
    - Tom Williams Retirement, 1946 (Box 21)
  - Portraits and miscellaneous family photographs (Box 21)
  - Dexter Mason Ferry, Jr.
    - In office (photo), 1958 (Box 21)
    - As part of group school photographs (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
      (include stereograph cards)
    - Photo albums, 1889-1896; 2 volumes (Box 21)
      (include photographs from Lawrenceville School, 1889-1891 of University of Michigan student life, 1892-1895 interior photos of family home at 31 Winder Street, Detroit, Michigan; photos of family members and travels)
  - Ferry family residences/Ferry Seed corporate sites (Box 22)
    (include photo of Godfrey Block, ca. 1900)
  - Dexter M. Ferry, Jr.
    - As part of musical groupings, 1890s (Box 22)
    - As part of Detroit High School and other groupings, 1890s (Box 22)
    - As part of miscellaneous groups, including Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, including Ferry Seed corporate officers, Dexter M. Ferry III (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, including exterior photo of an insurance building, Delta Kappa Epsilon house, and Wilfred Shaw woodcuts of University of Michigan views (Box 22)
  - Ferry family portraits (Box 23)
  - Dexter M. Ferry, Sr. portraits (Box 23)
- Memorabilia and later family materials
  - W. Hawkins Ferry, awards, tributes and commemoratives, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Dance cards and other social programs, mainly of Dexter M. Ferry, Jr., 1890s; 3 envelopes (Box 24)
  - University of Michigan medallion (Box 24)
  - Diplomas, resolutions, certificates, National Pin Co. cartoon (Box 24)